Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marko.
My name is Catherine and today we
have an advanced level lesson for you.
This one's a bit difficult.
It's all about science.
That's right.
Today we're going
to talk about physics
specifically about things
like Stephen Hawking
and wormholes, black holes and general
theory of relativity and all that good stuff.
Right.
So we're in class.
We're learning about physics today
and you're going to hear a lot of terms.
Don't worry if you're
not really sure what
they mean, we'll be
back in a moment to talk
about them.
Good morning everybody,
welcome to Physics 101.
My name is Ed Brown and I will
be a professor for this semester.
Since today is our
first day, I wanted to
give you an overview
of what this course will
look like, how you will be graded,
and what we will cover this semester.
Will we be focusing more on theoretical
physics or experimental physics professor?
This is an introductory
course and my aim
is to give you a broad
overview of the field
of physics, the term
physics encompasses many
different areas of research and study and
I hope this course will provide you with a
conceptual understanding
of physics, which will
prove useful whether or not you
choose to further your study in the field.
We will begin the
course by looking at the
fundamental concepts of
physics, then by the middle
of the semester, we will begin exploring
the more theoretical side of physics.
It is essential that you
first have a firm grasp
of the fundamentals,
so that you can better
understand the theoretical
concepts when we get to them.
Will we learn about black holes,
worm holes, and string theory?
We will learn about the general theory
of relativity, including black holes.
We will also explore
the developing theories
in quantum mechanics,
such as string theory.
We will discuss some hypothetical
features of spacetime like worm holes.
We will also explore
some of the more
influential developments
in the field of thermal
dynamics, electromagnetism,
and nuclear physics,
all of which have had
significant impacts on modern life.
Now I am going to have the
TAs pass out the syllabus for
this class, so you can see
how this course will be graded.
Oh man, it looks like this isn't going
to be the easy A I thought it'd be.
Alright, we are back so obviously we are
in a class as you said and the professor is
pretty much introducing the course and
what's going to happen during the semester.
That's right, so he is talking about the
different kinds of physics or the different
elements of physics that
will be a part of this course.
And there is a very
eager student, he is
very excited, and he
wants to know are these
interesting things going
to be a part of the course?
So when we start out,
we talked about these
two different fields
of physics, and I think
maybe it would be helpful to start there
with these two branches of this field.
That's right, he mentioned
this boy Matt said if
they are going to be focusing more on
theoretical physics or experimental physics.
Now theoretical
physics and experimental
physics are what we call
two different branches
of physics.
That means they are
both physics, but people
who do them have different methods
and maybe focus on different things.
Theoretical comes from
the word theory, so I
have a theory about something and I am
going to think about if whether or not it is
possible and maybe
there is a math involved.
But with experimental physics, the
keyword here is experiment, experimental.
That means we actually build
experiments to test our theories.
That's right, so I guess
theoretical physics
we can just have
theories about how things
happen or explain them,
but we can't really prove them.
We can just have theories
around them, maybe
we can try and prove
them mathematically.
But experimental physics,
you can actually, as
you said, create an
experiment to prove it or not.
That's right, and so those are the two main
branches that the young man asks about.
But the professor says,
"Listen, we are going
to be talking about the
fundamental concepts of physics.
"
And so fundamental
concepts are things that
you often hear a
professor talk about in your
introductory class, so introduction to
mathematics or introduction to physics.
So fundamental concepts are the basics.
That's right, so the
most important, but also
the ones at the very
bottom, the foundation
on because you can learn about more
difficult or more complicated things later.
But first you have to have a foundation,
so those are the fundamental concepts.
Right.
And actually after the professor said that
this guy, Matt, went on to ask if they were
going to learn about black holes,
worm holes, and string theory.
Okay, so three very important parts of
physics, but very, very complicated things.
The first two are related, right?
So we've got astrophysics,
astromine star, so
astrophysics is the
physics of things, bodies
in space, planets,
stars, things like that,
and so two concepts
that we often talk about
in astrophysics are black
holes and worm holes.
That's right, so I think many of you
have already heard this word of black hole.
The concept of it is basically a huge hole
in space that just sucks up everything.
The gravitational force,
so the pull of gravity
is so strong that
nothing can resist it.
Everything that comes close
to a black hole, it's like an drain.
to it, it gets sucked into it, right?
No light can escape it.
That's right.
And the other concept
there is a worm hole,
so it's basically a sort
of bending of space
and time in which you
can travel from one point to
another a lot faster than
going in the straight line.
So this is a very, very popular concept
in science fiction movies and books.
For example, Star Trek,
the most recent movie,
the New Movies Star Trek,
there was a worm hole.
So one ship goes from the
future and it comes into the past.
That's right.
So it has to travel through this worm hole.
And actually, yeah, you say science fiction
and obviously it's hard to prove it, but
this is one of the concepts that
physicists think they can prove someday.
And this is why it's a
part of theoretical physics.
That's right.
And what about this other
concept, string theory?
Okay, string theory is a theory about
the way the world works, basically.
And it is a theory that
actually competes with
Einstein's view of the
way the world works.
And string theory is
about basically strings
that are vibrating and that's the
way the entire universe is built.
Yeah, so basically at
the subatomic level,
usually you're supposed
to have an atom, but
also supposedly these atoms are made up of
strings that, depending on the frequency at
which they vibrate,
they could constitute
different elements or
different parts of matter.
Exactly.
And so we're talking about the very, very,
very, very, very, very, very, very, very
smallest building
blocks of the things in the
world, atoms and even carks
and jewels and those things.
Exactly.
So actually one of
these new things that,
well, people are talking
about string theory.
It's kind of this new
way of seeing the world
and explaining the
unexplainable because
there are so many things still in
the world that we can't explain.
And people argue about this
because obviously if you can't
prove it, it's hard to to say
what is right and what is wrong.
Exactly.
But actually one thing that was proven was
Einstein's general theory of relativity.
So this is something we all learned
back in high school or in college.
That's right.
So basically the general
theory of relativity
is this idea that space and
time are not fixed there.
They're relative to each other.
So an example my
teacher used to use is that
when you travel very, very, very fast,
imagine going around a jet around the world,
counterclockwise, time slows
down the faster you move.
Okay.
So that proves that time
and space are not fixed.
That's right.
This the general
theory of relativity and
specifically this aspect of
speed and time was proven
with the example
that you give with two
atomic clocks that you kept one on the
ground, like I don't know, in your house.
And you put one in an airplane that was
traveling faster than the speed of sound.
And so after maybe an hour
the plane would land and
the clocks would have
not the same time anymore.
It would be one, the
clock that was in the
airplane traveling faster
would be maybe half
a second off or
something very, very small.
But you would see that time move
to slower because your speed is faster.
All right.
So that's the general theory.
Oh, that's a part of the
general theory of relativity.
Right.
It's a very important
theory in the history
of the world, but also
the history of physics.
Another thing though
that the professor
mentioned that is very important in
physics these days is quantum mechanics.
Yes.
This is actually a very interesting field
of physics, but very hard to understand.
In my opinion, for
me, it's very, very hard.
I find it very complex too.
Well, mechanics are the
way things work, right?
And so quantum is at the
atomic and subatomic level.
And so you're talking
about basically the
building blocks of the
things in the universe.
And the people who
are studying this or
working on this, quantum mechanics,
they don't like the Einsteinians.
They don't like the people who follow
Einstein because these two theories.
They don't actually go together very well.
You either have to believe one
or you have to believe the other.
Well, the problem is
that when you're talking
about, when you're talking at the macro
level, the way things work and the way
things move, like for
example, you and me, of
course, they're formulas
and they're everything
that explains and that prove
that things are the way they are.
But the problem is that
in quantum mechanics
at its subatomic
level, it's so different.
Like for example,
electronics, the reason why
we're able to have
microprocessors and electronics
is because, for example,
atoms can be in two
places at the same time,
which is impossible in our world.
It's like saying, you know, Catherine can
be in two places at the exact same time.
And there's also this problem of
observation that I've read about.
So there are some
kinds of particles like
electrons, for example,
that if you're observing
them, sometimes up
here as waves, but if
you're observing them,
sometimes appear to have mass.
Exactly like light.
Yeah.
So you're talking about these things that
seem to have a whole different set of rules
from the rules that we have here walking
around and eating food and going to work.
And so I think that's what's fascinating
about physics, that you know, you can break
things down to the very smallest
parts and they seem very different.
Or you can think about
the stars and the moon
and these planets and they
have their own rules too.
Right.
And so that's why physics
is such a very, I think
it's frustrating and it's
exciting at the same time.
That's right.
And actually some
of the other fields that
the professors said they
were going to explore
are the fields of thermodynamics,
electromagnetism, and even nuclear physics.
So very important branches,
I think, of physics as well.
So when you're studying
physics or science, you will
definitely hear about the
laws of thermodynamics,
thermomines heat and dynamics
means, you know, changing, changing state.
And electromagnetism of
course is the combination
of two words, electricity and
magnetism, you know, like magnets.
You have the plus end and the minus
end and they attract or they repel them.
Then finally, nuclear
physics, nuclear physics
is very important
because it's again about
atoms and breaking down atoms
and finding out what their parts are.
So you might have heard
about the Hadron super collider.
Right.
This is like a big, it's
like a big racetrack
for atoms and they basically spin these
atoms around the racetrack, going faster and
faster and then they put objects in
their way so that they break, they crash.
And they study what the
what the pieces look like.
And what happens and how
much energy is is released.
It's all very interesting
and it seems like
things that are out of
science fiction because
it's not something
mainstream that you hear
about in the news very often or
that sometimes we understand.
Like obviously we all
hear about the gossip
magazines and who's
dating who and all this other
type of news, but very
rarely do we really pay
attention to this type of information or
news because it is a little bit complex to
understand and it seems
that I think scientists
are not the best writers for
average people like you and me.
They write in their own language almost.
Oftentimes that's the
case, but I have to say
I recently read Bill
Bryson's book, A Short
History of Nearly
Everything and it talks about
the history of the world
and us and the animals
and plants in it and
he talks about physics
especially and I think
that if you're interested
in that, I don't know,
I mean if you're an
advanced English learner,
it might be challenging,
it was challenging for
me, but it's definitely
a good book to read, to learn
about some of these things.
Yeah, it's actually a very good idea and I
don't know, many of us, I think many of us
as well growing up,
maybe we had a hard time
with some of these exact
sciences like chemistry or physics.
So we obviously find
it hard to be interested
in it, but you know
it's very different
because it's not math
and formulas, you don't
really have to know how to
derive the formula or anything.
You just kind of have
to understand the
theory and it's very,
very interesting I must say.
Because it's fun because
you can talk about,
it's like philosophy
sometimes you can talk
about, you know, if
this were the cases and
what would happen, it's
hypothetical situations
and I think that's
maybe more in line with
theoretical physics
but it's really interesting
to think about and to let your mind
go into these very strange places.
That's right.
So actually we are
curious to know if you
believe that maybe
someday we will be able to
travel in time or do you
believe that live in other planets
or we'll have space travel as
a part of our holiday making?
Yeah, they supposedly already are
arranging tourism to the moon, right?
Yeah, they are.
So I wonder if one
day like in the fifth
element we're going to
have these cruises to space.
Yeah, that would be fun.
So let us know what
your opinions are about
this topic and also if
you have any suggestions
or questions you can always visit us
on our website www.EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there
and until next time, bye bye.